Hi children, Ninan here and I am
here to add or to give value to everyone
who's watching this video.  Someone
asked me a question and said
they really had no idea about insurance.  So
what I did was I explained it to him in a
very simple way that everyone could understand.  So
I am here to show or to also explain to
you what insurance is.  Okay, let's say I
have here a whole tissue paper and
let's say that this whole tissue
paper is your income.  Okay?  This is
your salary or
income received monthly or when you get
paid.  So the only thing they will do is get
insurance because they think otherwise,
insurance is just an expense.  It's just
additional um that can add
to their monthly expenses or um quarterly
expenses.  But the truth is,
insurance is not an expense.
Insurance is, let's say, savings for
our loved ones.  So let's go back
to tissue paper.
We call this the pinch system.  Yes.  Is it
pinched?  Are you still pinching?  That's what the person I
was waiting for said,
who is this?  Neither does Katrine Bernardo.
Okay.  So let's go back.  This is one
whole tissue paper, my dears.
Let's just pinch.  Let's just pinch a little.
This is your income.  And
we will just take a few percentages from
your income.  So this is what we pinched.
Very small part.  It's still intact.
This is your income.  Still the same size.  And
this is what we pinched.  Small.  So when
something happens, aren't there
really events in our lives
that we don't expect?
You know, you could have an accident, especially
nowadays, we can't tell,
no matter how careful we are,
accidents still happen.  So for example,
you had an accident and were there or
really
[Music]
um you've finished your run.   The
Lord has really called you that way.
For example, that.  So this income
that your family,
your children, your spouse, your parents,
your siblings expect, of course, this
income will automatically disappear.
Let's throw it away like that.  So he's gone.
What will be left and what will those
you left behind in your life expect?  So
you see how we pinched it?  This
little pinch we've already given you, which
you persevered with and didn't think was an
expense.  That will one day
rebuild the lost income.  Since you're gone
, the income is gone, but
they have a reliable income.  So that's
insurance, godchildren.  Okay?  Don't
think of it as an expense because it's just a small
pinch of your income, a
little savings, and instead of saving
everywhere else, set aside some for insurance.
And again, the one that was lost earlier,
you plucked that little pinch
.  He's whole again.
So that's it parents and I hope that
I was able to give or add value to
everyone and happy Sunday.
Bye.  Muah.